lmcu.org 2016-04-11

# FACTS

                                                                                                   Rev. 12/2013
                        WHAT DOES Lake Michigan Credit Union
FACTS                   DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
Why?                    Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives
                        consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you
                        how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to
                        understand what we do.
What?                   The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you
                        have with us. This information can include:
                              Social Security number and Income
                              Account Balances        and Payment History
                              Credit History          and Credit Scores
How?                    All financial companies need to share members’ personal information to run their everyday
                        business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their
                        members’ personal information; the reasons Lake Michigan Credit Union
                        chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
                                                                      Does Lake Michigan
       Reasons we can share your personal information                 Credit Union share?    Can you limit this sharing?
For our everyday business purposes –
such as to process your transactions, maintain
your account(s), respond to court orders and legal                             Y                            N
investigations, or report to credit bureaus
For our marketing purposes –
to offer our products and services to you                                      Y                            Y
For joint marketing with other financial companies                             Y                            Y
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes –
information about your transactions and experiences                            Y                            Y
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes –
Information about your creditworthiness                                        N                   WE DON’T SHARE
For our affiliates to market to you                                            Y                            Y
For nonaffiliates to market to you                                             N                   WE DON’T SHARE
                        • Call 616-242-9790 – our menu will prompt you through your choice(s) or
To limit our            • Visit us online: www.lmcu.org – “Contact Us”, then secure contact form.
sharing                 Please note:
                        If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information 15 days from the date we sent
                        this notice. When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as
                        described in this notice.
                        However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.
Questions?              Call 616-242-9790 or go to www.lmcu.org

Who we are
Who is providing this notice?                    Lake Michigan Credit Union
What we do
How does Lake Michigan Credit Union protect To protect your personal information from unauthorized access
my personal information?                         and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law.
                                                 These measures include computer safeguards and secured files
                                                 and buildings.
How does Lake Michigan Credit Union              We collect your personal information, for example, when you
collect my personal information?                      Open an account               or Deposit Money
                                                      Pay your bills                or Apply for a loan
                                                      Use your credit or debit card
                                                 We also collect your personal information from others such as credit
                                                 bureaus, affiliates or other companies.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?                   Federal law gives you the right to limit only
                                                      sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes - information
                                                          about your creditworthiness
                                                      affiliates from using your information to market to you
                                                      sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
                                                 State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to
                                                 limit sharing.
What happens when I limit sharing                Your choice will apply to everyone on your account.
for an account I hold jointly with
someone else?
Definitions
Affiliates                                      Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                                financial and nonfinancial companies.
                                                     Lake Michigan Financial Group (including Lake Michigan
                                                         Insurance Agency)
Nonaffiliates                                   Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                                financial and nonfinancial companies.
                                                     LMCU does not share with nonaffiliates.
Joint Marketing                                 A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that
                                                together market financial products or services to you.
                                                     Our joint marketing partners include insurance and student loan
                                                         companies.
Other Important information
What members can do to help: Protect your account numbers, card numbers, and passwords. Use caution in revealing
account numbers, social security numbers, etc., to other persons.
